http://www.citizencope.com/privacy-policy

Contact
CITIZEN COPE - PRIVACY POLICYLast updated: February 1st, 2020Citizen Cope ("us", "we", or "our") operates https://www.citizencope.com (the "Site"). This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information we receive from users of the Site.We use your Personal Information only for providing and improving the Site. By using the Site, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.Controller’s Contact DetailsCitizen Cope is the controller for the personal information we process, unless otherwise stated.You can contact us via email at any of the addresses provided on our contact page at https://citizencope.com/contactOur postal address is 15760 Ventura Blvd., Ste. 1020, Encino, CA 91436, USA.Data Protection Officer’s Contact DetailsOur Data Protection Officer is Taylor Weekly. You can contact her at taylor@citizencope.com or via our postal address. Please mark the envelope ‘Data Protection Officer’.OverviewMaintaining the security of your data is a priority at Citizen Cope, and we are committed to respecting your privacy rights. We pledge to handle your data fairly and legally at all times. We are also dedicated to being transparent about what data we collect about you and how we use it.This policy, which applies whether you visit our website on line or otherwise engage with us provides you with information about:how we use your data;what personal data we collect;how we ensure your privacy is maintained; andyour legal rights relating to your personal data.ConsentIn specific situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent. For example, when you tick a box to receive email newsletters. When collecting your personal data, we’ll always make clear to you which data is necessary in connection with a particular service.Legitimate InterestIn specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests.For example, we will use your purchase history to send you or make available personalized offers. We will also send you direct marketing emails when you shop with us and do not choose to opt out - this is often called a 'soft opt in'.We also combine the browsing history of many customers to identify trends and ensure we can keep up with demand, or develop new products/services. We may also use your address details to send you direct marketing information by post, telling you about products and services that we think might interest you.With your consent, or when you shop with us and do not choose to opt out from receiving our emails ('soft opt in') we may use your personal data, preferences and details of your transactions to keep you informed by email, web, text, telephone and through our contact centers about relevant products and services including tailored special offers, discounts, promotions, events, competitions and so on.Information Collection And UseWhile using our Site, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to your name, address, and online identifiers ("Personal Information").The collection of this information is performed via the following methods: account creation, making a purchase, browsing the website, downloading our app, engaging with us on social media, completing surveys we send, when you contact us.CommunicationsWe may use your Personal Information to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other relevant information and may further combine information with demographic information, publicly available records and other third party information sources. We may use this information to provide you with a customized experience and to develop and promote our products and services. Personal information is not shared with third parties.Log DataLike many site operators, we collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Site ("Log Data").This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Site that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this data.CookiesCookies are files with small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and stored on your computer's hard drive.Like many sites, we use "cookies" to collect information. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Site.Data RetentionWhenever we collect or process your personal data, we’ll only keep it for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.At the end of that retention period, your data will either be deleted completely or anonymized, for example by aggregation with other data so that it can be used in a non-identifiable way for statistical analysis and business planning.Data ProcessingSometimes we will need to share your personal data with third parties and suppliers outside of the United States of America, such as the European Economic Area (EEA) or Canada. If we do this, we have procedures in place to ensure your data receives the same protection as if it were being processed inside the United States of America. For example, our contracts with third parties stipulate the standards they must follow at all times.Any transfer of your personal data will follow applicable laws and we will treat the information under the guiding principles of this Privacy Notice.SecurityThe security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. We secure access to all transactional areas of our websites and apps using ‘https’ technology. Access to your personal data is password-protected, and sensitive data such as payment card information) is secured and tokenized to ensure it is protected.While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.Your rightsUnder GDPR and CCPA, our European and Californian customers have the right to request:Access to the personal data we hold about you, free of charge in most cases.The correction of your personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete.The deletion of the data we hold about you, in specific circumstances; for example, when you withdraw consent or object, and we have no legitimate overriding interest, or once the purpose for which we hold the data has come to an end (such as the end of a warranty). A computer file in a common format (CSV or similar) containing the personal data that you have previously provided to us, and the right to have your information transferred to another entity where this is technically possible.Restriction of the use of your personal data, in specific circumstances, generally while we are deciding on an objection you have made. That we stop processing your personal data, in specific circumstances; for example, when you have withdrawn consent, or object for reasons related to your individual circumstances.That we stop using your personal data for direct marketing (either through specific channels, or all channels).That we stop any consent-based processing of your personal data after you withdraw that consent.Review by a Partner of any decision made based solely on automatic processing of your data (so where no human has yet reviewed the outcome and criteria for the decision).You can contact us to request to exercise these rights at any time via any of the contact methods listed above or at https://citizencope.com/contact.If we choose not to action your request, we will explain the reasons for our refusal. Your right to withdraw consentWhenever you have given us your consent to use your personal data, you have the right to change your mind at any time and withdraw that consent.Where we rely on our legitimate interestIn cases where we are processing your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest, you can ask us to stop for reasons connected to your individual situation. We must then do so unless we believe we have a legitimate overriding reason to continue processing your personal data, such as administration of an extended warranty.Direct marketingYou have the right to stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing activity through all channels, or selected channels. We must always comply with your request.Checking your identityTo protect the confidentiality of your information, we will ask you to verify your identity before proceeding with any request you make under this Privacy Notice. If you have authorized a third party to submit a request on your behalf, we will ask them to prove they have your permission to act.Changes To This Privacy PolicyThis Privacy Policy is effective as of February 1st, 2020 and will remain in effect except with respect to any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after being posted on this page.We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time and you should check this Privacy Policy periodically. Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy.We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy at any time by posting a new Privacy Policy on our website.Contact UsIf you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at https://citizencope.com/contact.
Subscribe
Sign up with your email address to receive news and updates.
Thank you!
Back To Top
